

CONTACT

- +237 656 832 062
- Omnisports, Yoaoundé, Cameroun



EDUCATION

2018 - 2021 INSTITUT SAINT JEAN

- PROFESSIONAL LICENSE APPLICATION DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT
- Yaoundé

2017 - 2018 COLLÈGE DE LA RÉUNIFICATION

- SCIENTIFIC BACCALAUREATE
- Bafoussam

SKILLS

- Java
- Spring boot
- Microservice
- API REST
- Git
- Oauth 2
- Jwt
- Swagger v3

LANGUAGES

English : beginnerFrench : fluent

MAXIMILIEN KENGNE KONGNE

JAVA SPRING BOOT DEVELOPPER

PROFILE

Motivated by the desire to be an expert in microservice, I now have two years of experience in microservice architectures with the java framework, spring boot. So I would like to put my skills at the service of your company and learn from you at the same time in order to pursue my objective. Reliable and able to work independently as well as in a team, I have good analytical skills and real initiative in problem solving. I do technology monitoring to stay up to date on the latest trends.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sprint Pay

2023 - PRESENT

Java Spring Boot Developper

Project 2: Development of a registration management platform and note from the professional insurance training center.

Project 1: Development of a risk management an internal control solution for SOMDIAA (https://somdia.sprint-pay.com/)

Architecture implemented:

Microservice backend

Modules supported:

management note, Plan d'action and controle interne

Technologies:

 Architecture microservice, Spring Boot, MySQL, Spring data, jUnit, Mockito, jwt, Spring Security, Redis, Kafka, OpenFeign, Jira

Freelance

2022 - 2023

Java Spring Boot Developper

Project: Design and development of a job offer web application.

Architecture implemented:

Microservice backend

Modules supported:

offer, talent, library, useful, security, notification, registry and gateway microservice.

Technologies:

Spring Boot, MySQL, Spring data, jUnit, Mockito, jwt, Spring Security, Redis, Kafka, OpenFeign, Jira

HOBBIES

- Programming
- Cinema
- Music



CONTACT

- +237 656 832 062
- Omnisports, Yoaoundé, Cameroun



23 Septembre 1995

FORMATION

2018 - 2021 INSTITUT SAINT JEAN

- LICENCE PROFESSIONNELLE

 CONCEPTION ET

 DEVELOPPEMENT
 D'APPLICATION
- Yaoundé

2017 - 2018 COLLÈGE DE LA RÉUNIFICATION

- BACCALAUREAT D
- Bafoussam

COMPETENCES

- Java
- · Spring boot
- Microservice
- API REST
- Git
- Oauth 2
- Jwt
- Swagger v3

LANGUES

Anglais : débutantFrançais : courant

MAXIMILIEN KENGNE KONGNE

DÉVELOPPEUR JAVA SPRING BOOT

PROFIL

Motivé par l'envie d'être un expert en microservice, j'ai aujourd'hui deux ans d'expérience dans les architectures microservices avec le framework java, spring boot. Je souhaite donc mettre mes compétences au service de votre entreprise et apprendre par la même occasion de vous afin de poursuivre mon objectif. Fiable et capable de travailler de manière autonome ainsi qu'en équipe, je possède de bonnes capacités d'analyse et une réelle initiative dans la résolution de problèmes. Je fais de la veille technologique pour rester au courant des dernières tendances.

EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONNELLE

Sprint Pay

2023 - PRESENT

Développeur Java Spring Boot

Projet 2 : Développement d'une plateforme de gestion des inscriptions et note du centre de formation professionnelle en assurance.

Projet 1: Développement d'une solution de gestion des risques et de contrôle interne pour SOMDIAA (https://somdia.sprint-pay.com/)

Architecture mise en œuvre:

Micro service backend

Modules pris en charge:

management note, Plan d'action et contrôle interne

Technologies:

Spring Boot, MySQL, Spring data, jUnit, Mockito, jwt, Spring Security, Redis, Kafka, OpenFeign, Jira

Freelance 2022 - 2023

Développeur Java Spring Boot

Projet : Conception et développement d'une application web d'offres d'emploi.

Architecture mise en œuvre:

Micro service backend

Modules pris en charge:

offer, talent, library, useful, security, notification, registry and gateway micro service.

Technologies:

Spring Boot, MySQL, Spring data, jUnit, Mockito, jwt, Spring Security, Redis, Kafka, OpenFeign, Jira

CENTRE D'INTERETS

- Programmation
- Cinéma
- Musique